LINH HUYNH

718-986-4923 - linh44h@gmail.com - LinkedIn - GitHub - Website

Crafty Full Stack Developer with experience in Ruby on Rails and ReactJs. I am a fun loving former tour guide; a creative and flexible human being with a burning passion for perfection and analytical thinking. My background as a data coordinator has prepared me to tackle challenging tasks, keep an eye on small details, and work closely with end users. I always strive to keep improving and am now committed to building my career as a software developer.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby on Rails | JavaScript | ¡Query | React | Redux | Node | HTML5 | CSS3 | SQL | Semantic UI | API | Jest

EDUCATION

FLATIRON School, NY

Aug 2018 - Nov 2018 - 15 week intensive bootcamp. Full Stack Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript.

HUTECH University, HCMC, Vietnam & LINCOLN University, Oakland, CA – Bachelor's Degree

2011 - 2014 - Business Administration and Management

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Split-B - Frontend | Backend | Demo | Live - Username: hi - Password: hi

An app that lets users split a bill among friends

- Server-side: Ruby on Rails & Client-side: ReactJs & Redux
- Implemented Google OCR API to parse text from the receipts which rendered more accurate values than other APIS.
- Used Redux for state management and maintain the structure of application
- Created Mobile First Application with Responsive Design to target mobile users.

Go Stamp! - Frontend | Backend | Demo | Live - Username: hi - Password: hi

Collect digital stamps every time you visit the stores to redeem great deals!

- Server-side: Ruby on Rails & Client-side: ReactJs
- Incorporated JWT and local storage to store encrypted user information
- Created a single-page application using react-router-dom for fast loading time and caching local storage effectively
- Applied Responsive view for User Interface, styling front-end with Semantic UI & Pure CSS

Tic Tap Tone - Frontend | Backend | Demo | Live

A fun game that tests and enhances auditory and visual reaction times while challenging memory skills

- Server-side: Ruby on Rails & Client-side: Vanilla JS
- Enabled sounds and keyboards to improve User Experience along with timer to increase the complexity
- Designed front-end with Bootstrap and Pure CSS

EXPERIENCE

EPI Services, LLC, Brooklyn, NY — *Data Coordinator*

Dec 2016 - Aug 2018

- Identified 2 underserved markets and developed a plan to expand services resulting in lower operational costs.
- Created and maintained an Excel database of over 10,000 records to monitor company's performance. Created and ran reports using Excel dashboard.

Back of the Bike Tours, HCMC, Vietnam — *Tour Operator*

May 2015 - Apr 2016

- Created a customer feedback program to train employees to overcome the cultural barrier between guides and tourists.
- Contributed to the rise of the company's Tripadvisor popularity and profile from 5th to 1st.

Softer Source. HCMC. Vietnam – Researcher

May 2014 - Apr 2015

• Effectively facilitated communication between outsourcing clients and iOS developers ensuring high-quality customer experience, which resulted in new client referrals.

AWARDS